Kai-Wen Luo 羅凱文

+886 922 572 491 / kevinluo201@gmail.com

Profile

I have been practicing programming skill over 10 years (especially Web-related technologies), which is my hobby and also a practical skill. I have become a full-stack engineer since the beginning of my career. Moreover, one of my favorite things at work is to understand the relation between the business and the software, by which I can design the software more reasonable and useful.

"Never limit myself" is probably the most suitable phrase to describe me. I love to learn or do new things. For example, I have expertise in CAD to draw building's facade and internal decoration; I held sessions voluntarily to teach people how to program; and I also like to cook and read in my leisure time.

Skills Highlights

- Ruby on Rails
- Javascript, Vue.js
- Deploying

- Complex problem solver
- Cooperative
- English, TOFEL iBT 90, TOEIC 900

I am familiar with each part to build a web application. therefore, not only I could make things from scratch but also be good at refactoring the legacy code. Ruby on Rails(RoR) is my main tool to build web application, RoR provides a good MVC pattern simplifying the complexity of database access and writing program logic.

I am a believer of the KISS principle (keep it simple and stupid). It reflects in my coding style and my working style. I use to work with people from different areas and I found KISS principle really works and decrease the chance of misunderstanding significantly.

Experience

CTO, CHUANBOX(STARTUP); SHANGHAI, CHINA – 2018-2019NOV

Type of business: fashion, subscription e-commerce

As a tech leader in a startup, I do various works, however, I have two main responsibilities: **developing the system** and **managing the IT team.**

The system is composed by websites for customers and internal usage. For customers usage, I developed a mobile single page application to let users become members and pay for the orders. For internal usage, an administrative site for managing members, warehouse items, orders, etc. was built.

I am in charge of recruiting I.T. personnels, training them and also assign each one appropriate tasks according to the schedule. To manage the team better, I imported

many modern Devops methods and techniques like Agile, Docker, etc. and then use them in daily development.

FREELANCER - 2016-PRESENT

Type of business: building websites

My vision of building applications has developed more thoroughly in this time. Comparing to my daytime job, which the system were already there waiting other to enhance it, I need to utilize all my knowledge to conduct a freelancer's project: frontend to backend, deploy the application to some Linux VPS in the cloud and performance analysis.

I am asked to attend many meetings to discuss the requirements with the customers very often. This process makes me used to communicate with people from different area.

PROGRAMMER, OTTO GROUP; TAIPEI, TAIWAN - 2014-2016

Type of business: e-commerce

My main responsibility is to analyze the requirements or problems, and then propose algorithmic solutions for other developers to implement. As Otto group is the second largest e-commerce company in the world, it has really huge amount of data. A trivial solution can easily decrease system efficiency or even lead to disaster. To prevent that, the proposed solutions would have been reviewed by many senior employees, thus my ability to solve problem was also refined.

PROGRAMMER, FORMOSA SOFT; TAIPEI, TAIPEI - 2013-2014

Type of business: education-related software

My job in this company is to build a PowerPoint-like software written in C#.Net. Because of this job, I am very used to develop both UI components and the logic behind user interaction, which is why I become full-stack web developer naturally.

Education

Master - Computer Science, National Tsing Hua University - 2009-2012

CVGIP 2011 Best Paper Award

Exchange Student — Multimedia Engineer, Université Paris-Est Marne-la-Vallée, France — 2011-2012

• Elite Scholarship from Ministry of Education

Bachelor - Computer Science, National Tsing Hua University - 2005-2009